General Manuscripts Miscellaneous Collection, 1502-2012: Finding Aid C0140
Manuscripts Division
- Elizabeth Dilling Publications, circa 1962-1965; Dilling, Elizabeth, 1894-1966; 1 folder (Box B-001856, Folder 18)
  Consists of a group of publications created by Elizabeth Dilling (1894-1966), a far-right extremist and activist who engaged in anti-communist, anti-Semitic, and isolationist movements in the United States from the 1930s through the 1960s. Included in this group of materials are six issues of the Dilling Bulletin (July-August 1962; Christmas 1963; January-February 1964; March-April 1964; July-August 1964; and September-December 1965); a Red Network Bulletin ("Dare We Oppose Red Treason?"); and a tabloid paper distributed by Gordon Winrod reprinting Dilling's anti-Semitic tract, "Jews Not a Race: A World Pharisee Sect."
  These materials contain anti-Semitic and racist hate speech throughout.
  Anti-Communist movements -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Antisemitism -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Propaganda, Anti-communist -- 20th century; Right-wing extremists -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Serials (publications) -- 20th century
- Comunita Ortodossa di Coo, 1933-1939; Petros Vergos; 1 folder (Box B-002011, Folder 1)
  Acquired with matching funds provided by the Program in Hellenic Studies with the support of the Stanley J. Seeger Hellenic Fund. (AM 2023-016)
  Consists of 104 documents regarding the Orthodox Community of Kos, Greece, its local history, the municipal elections, the financial support of the schools (especially from the Greek government), several educational matters, the reconstruction of the church of St. Nicholas, the restoration services of the the earthquake in 1933, and many more.
  Documents are numbered 1-103 and 105 (many with accompanying documents), in their majority of the Regional Office of Public Safety of Kos and the Central Office of Public Safety of Rhodes, including correspondence either from the first office to Reggenza del Governo in Kos and from the second office to the Segretario Generale del Governo in Rhodes; in the last documents, the office of Rhodes refers directly to the governor de Vecchi). Kos and Rhodes, February 6 1933 – March 20, 1939. Total, 211 pages in several sizes. Clippings of the newspaper "Il Messaggero di Rodi" are attached in six documents.
  Petros Vergos